# AMR ABDELHADY ALI

## iOS Developer







## **SUMMARY**

+2 years experience, i'm one who loves challenges and makes me motivated, my usual is to handled graduation project, full-time job, student activity, advanced swift course, at same time, the one who leaves instant impact whatever the business type, I worked on product based, software house, solo or with teams, remote or in office employee, after learning about android, web design, database, I found my passion creating iOS Apps, and i'm searching for the next limit to break

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- CoreData, CoreAnimation
- OOP, SOLID Principles
- iOS App / View Life Cycle
- Git
- Agile methodology
- Apple UI/UX Standards
- Storyboard , SnapKit
- Protocols, Delegation
- MVC, MVVM, MVP, VIPER
- Threading and Concurrency Google Maps, MapKit
- -Unit-Testing

## **EDUCATION**

## **Suez Canal University**

Computer Science Bachelor - 2019.

- President, Ressala Charity Organization
- Team Leader, Logistics team - responsible for event planning

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Mid-Level iOS Developer

Medica Healthy | AUG 2020 - Present

- Revamped client and provider apps
- Fastly adapt on previous developer code, with architecture I never worked on before, lunched my fully written feature within 2 weeks

Portfolio

Mobile: +201020845933 theamr.ali@gmail.com

Al Mohandseen, Giza, Egypt

- Worked on features like Video Calls, Payment, Chating, Maps and Tracking
- Become one of decision makers on projects with technical knowledge or customer vision
- Created UI programmatically , with VIPER architecture pattern
- Enhanced app performance with new ways of caching and memory management

## Junior iOS Developer

Chatomaps | Feb 2020 - July 2020

- I published company main app
- With my experience working on leagcy code I worked on existed features, imporved and maintaining the code base was my challenge
- Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to maximize development efficiency. leading the project to new level of performance

## FreeLance iOS Developer

Microtech Saudi | Apr 2019 - Oct 2019

- · Designed and build the application for the iOS platform
- My work was remote and showed responsibility and commitment at young age
- My hard challenge is to deliver features as a quacks as possible with my other full time job and collage responsibilities

## Trainee iOS Developer

Hamza Software House | Sep 2018 - June 2019

- I started the iOS section in company, turning the android versions to iOS
- As my first Full-time job, with full responsibility of iOS apps, working solo, I learned a lot and helped company to standup and build base of trust with customers

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- <u>Lint School</u>, Advanced iOS Development Aug 2021
- IT-Share, Android Development Aug 2018
- Applied Syndicate, Adobe Certified Web Designer June 2016